(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-03T21:46:34.445586",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.7-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
唸るぜ 血反吐ついたって 守りたい
I'll roar, even if I spit blood, I want to protect you,
革命道中で 君に夢中
in the midst of revolution, I'm crazy about you.
暗闇染み込む世界で見つけた
Found in a world soaked in darkness,
センチメンタルな恋
a sentimental love.
甘くのたろんだ眼差し
A sweet, languid gaze,
変に色気あるから困った
it's strangely alluring, and I'm at a loss.
手を繋ぐ勇気出したくて
Wanting to summon the courage to hold hands,
身の程わきまえてちゃ出来ないね
I can't do it if I just know my place.
暗いトンネルの壁 滴り落ちる秘密
On the walls of a dark tunnel, dripping secrets,
しなやかに高鳴る心
a heart throbbing gracefully.
ダメダメ
No, no!
待て待て
Wait, wait!
呪いも病も抱きしめたい
I want to embrace both curses and sickness
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいかな
Is it okay if I go wild around here?
あー唸るぜ
Ah, I'll let out a roar!
舌打ちついたって守りたい
Even if you click your tongue, I want to protect you
革命道中だって 君に夢中
Even in the midst of revolution, I'm crazy about you!
暗闇染み込む世界で見つけた
In a world steeped in darkness, I found it:
センチメンタルな恋
A sentimental love.
なりふり構わず側にいたい
Regardless of appearances, I want to stay by your side
不器用な君にも期待しちゃうよ
I can't help expecting things from you, clumsy as you are
しがみつけば消えそうな火に
To a flame that seems ready to die out if clung to,
恋の爪立てて近づいて
digging in the claws of love, I draw near,
身を任せ抱かれて 全て失ってもいい
surrendering to your embrace, I wouldn't mind losing everything.
しなやかに高鳴る心
My heart beats gracefully and fast.
ダメダメ
No, no!
待て待て
Wait, wait!
呪いも病も君となら
With curses and sickness, if it's with you,
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいかな
is it okay if I go wild around here?
あー泣けるぜ 絶句しちゃうまで 離れない
Ah, it brings tears; until I'm speechless, I won't let go
革命道中だって 君に夢中
Even in the midst of revolution, I'm crazy about you!
彷徨う旅の狭間で見つけた
In the spaces between our wandering journey, I found it:
センチメンタルな恋
A sentimental love.
突き進むなら二人で
If we push forward, let's do it together
革命道中だって 夢に熱中
Even in the midst of revolution, engrossed in our dream!
ダメダメ
No, no!
待て待て
Wait, wait!
呪いも病も抱きしめたい
I want to embrace both curses and sickness
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいよね
It's totally fine to go wild around here, right?
怖くたって唸るぜ
Even if it's scary, I'll let out a roar!
舌打ちついたって 守りたい
Even if you click your tongue, I want to protect you
革命道中だって 君に夢中
Even in the midst of revolution, I'm crazy about you!
暗闇染み込む世界で見つけた
In a world steeped in darkness, I found it:
センチメンタルな恋
A sentimental love.
Catch the Moment
[Song: Catch the Moment]
いくぞー！
Here we go!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
そっと吐き出す ため息を吸い込んだ
I breathed in the sigh I softly exhaled,
後悔は苦い味残して
leaving behind a bitter taste of regret.
いつも なんで？ 肝心なこと言えないまま
Why is it that, always unable to say what matters most,
次の朝日が顔だしてる
the next morning sun shows its face?
嫌になった運命を ナイフで切り刻んで
Carving up this repulsive fate with a knife,
もう一度
if I were to start all over again,
やり直したらキミに出会えないかも
I might never get to meet you.
僕の声が響いた瞬間に始まる
The moment my voice resonated,
命のリミット 心臓がカウントしてる
the limit of life began, my heart counting down.
叶えても叶えても
No matter how many wishes come true,
終わらない願い
the wishing never ends.
汗をかいて走った
Sweating as I ran,
世界の秒針は いつか止まった僕を置いていく
the world's second hand leaves behind my halted self.
あと何回キミと笑えるの？
How many more times can I laugh with you?
試してるんだ 僕を
It's testing me—
Catch the Moment
一個幸せを数えるたびに
Every time I count one piece of happiness,
変わっていく未来に怯えてしまうけど
I find myself frightened of the changing future, but...
愛情の種を大切に育てよう
let's cherish and nurture this seed of affection.
分厚い雲もやがて 突き破るかな
I wonder if it will eventually break through the thick clouds.
キミの声が響いた
Your voice resonated,
僕の全身を通って 心臓のドアをノックしてる
passing through my whole body and knocking on my heart's door.
「臆病」でも開けちゃうんだよ
Even if I'm "cowardly," I end up opening it,
信じたいから
because I want to believe.
何にもないと思ったはずの足元に
Beneath my feet, where I thought there was nothing at all,
いつか深く確かな...
someday deep, sure [roots will grow]...
確かな根を生やす
...it will take deep, solid root.
嵐の夜が来たとしても
Even if a stormy night comes,
揺らいだりはしない 何度でも
I won't ever waver, no matter how many times.
追いついたり 追い越したり
Catching up, overtaking...
キミがふいに分かんなくなって
Suddenly losing sight of you...
息をしたタイミングが合うだけで
Just breathing at the exact same moment...
嬉しくなったりして
makes me feel so happy.
集めた一秒を
If every second we've gathered...
永遠にして
could turn into eternity,
行けるかな
I wonder if we can go on?
僕の声が響いた瞬間に始まる
The moment my voice echoes out, it begins.
命のリミット 心臓がカウントしてる
The limit of life, my heart is counting down.
叶えても 叶えても
Even if fulfilled, even if granted,
終わらない願い
these wishes never end.
汗をかいて走った 世界の秒針が
I ran dripping with sweat, and the world's clock...
いつか止まった僕を置いていく
leaves me behind whenever I come to a halt.
あと何回 キミと笑えるの？
How many more times can I laugh with you?
試してるんだ 僕を Catch the Moment
It's testing me... Catch the Moment!
逃さないよ 僕は
I won't let it slip away,
この瞬間を掴め
I'll seize this moment!
Catch the Moment
こんばんドドド～！
Good evening, dododo~!
お誕生日を2回迎えることとなった角巻わためです！
I'm Tsunomaki Watame, celebrating my birthday twice!
本当は6月6日が誕生日なんですけど、
My birthday was actually on June 6th, but...
ぐるぐるが多くて中断、そして延期になり、
with all the buffering, it was stopped and postponed...
今日！「角巻わため生誕祭2026 アニソンNight Fever 2」
And today, "Tsunomaki Watame Birthday 2026: Anisong Night Fever 2"...
改めて開催させていただくことになりました～！
is officially being held anew~!
迅速に動いてくださった運営さんたち、
To the staff who acted so quickly,
そしてライブを観に来てくれている皆さん！
and to everyone here watching the live show!
本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so very much!
1曲目『革命道中』、2曲目『Catch the Moment』と、
Starting with Song 1 "Kakumei Douchuu" and Song 2 "Catch the Moment",
観ていただいて分かった方もいるかもしれないんですが、
some of you watching might have already realized,
前回のライブで放送した部分は、
the parts that aired during the previous live stream...
万が一のために録画を回してくださっていたので、
were recorded just in case, so...
そちらの6月6日のバキバキ生誕当日のパフォーマンスを観ていただいて、
you got to see that high-energy performance from the actual birthday on June 6th!
それ以外のその後のMCは、改めて、
And as for the MC parts after that and beyond,
これ以上ライブ延期にならないように、
so the live wouldn't be postponed any further,
今回は事前に収録をさせていただきました～！
we pre-recorded everything in advance this time~!
なので、未来のリアルタイムのみんなのコメントを
So, while trying to predict everyone's real-time comments...
予知しながらMCしたいなと思いますので、
from the future as I do this MC,
いっぱいコメントしてください！
please send lots and lots of comments!
うんうんうん！分かったよ、はい！はい！うん！
Yeah, yeah, yeah! Got it! Yes! Yes! Uh-huh!
あ、ありがとうね、おめでとうもありがとう！
Ah, thank you! Thank you for the birthday wishes too!
見える、見えるぞ～！
I can see them! I can see them~!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
説明はここまで！
That's all for the explanation!
ここからはいつものライブ！
From here on, it's the usual live show!
今日は生誕ライブなので、たくさんこのライブに向けて
Since today is my birthday live, for this show,
準備や練習を本当にたくさんしてきました！
I practiced and prepared so, so much!
是非最後まで楽しんで、そしていっぱいお祝いしてもらえると嬉しいです！
Please enjoy until the very end, and I'd love it if you celebrate lots with me!
本日のハッシュタグはこちら！
Today's hashtag is this right here!
6月6日と変わらず、「#角巻わため生誕祭2026」になりますので、
Just like on June 6th, it's "#角巻わため生誕祭2026", so...
たくさんスクショとか感想とかポストしてください！
please post plenty of screenshots and impressions!
目指せ！またトレンド…ドゥルルルル…
Aim for... trending... *drumroll*...
1位！
Number one!
後でじっとりねっとりわためも見に行きたいと思ってますので、
Watame wants to go creep and read through all of them later,
よろしくお願いします！
so please make lots of posts!
では、ここまで『ダンダダン』の『革命道中』、
Now then, so far I sang "Kakumei Douchuu" from Dandadan,
『ソードアート・オンライン』の『Catch the Moment』と歌わせていただいたんですが、
and "Catch the Moment" from Sword Art Online...
アニメや原曲MVに関連している演出を入れ込んだりしているので、
We included effects and staging related to the anime and original MVs,
みんな分かったかな？
so did you all catch that?
ターボわためイトとか分かったかな？
Did you notice Turbo Watamete and everything?
是非細かいところまで見てもらえると嬉しいです！
I hope you enjoy checking out all the fine details!
ここからはゲストパートもあります！
From here on, we have the guest section!
みんなの好きなアニソンも出てくるかも？
Maybe your favorite anime songs will come up too?
ということで、ゲストパート盛り上がっていきましょう！
So with that, let's get hyped for the guest segment!
割れた鏡の中
In the shattered mirror,
映る君の姿
your reflected figure.
泣いている 泣いている
You're crying, you're crying,
細い月をなぞる指
your finger tracing the slender moon.
誰を呼んでいるの
Who are you calling out to?
消えた恋の背中
The fading silhouette of a lost love.
何度でも 何度でも
Again and again, no matter how many times,
君の窓を叩くから
I'll keep knocking on your window.
夜の加速度に 背中押されて
Pushed forward by the acceleration of the night,
糸が切れる様に
like a snapping thread,
ただ、君を 君を強く
I just held you, held you tight,
抱いてた
in my arms.
アンバランスな
With an unbalanced...
Kissを交わして 愛に近づけよ
...kiss exchanged, let's draw closer to love.
君の涙も 哀しい嘘も
Both your tears and your sad lies,
僕の心に
within my heart,
眠れ
let them rest.
昨日へのMerry-go-round 君を運んでゆく
The merry-go-round to yesterday carries you away.
止めたくて 止めたくて
Wanting to stop it, wanting to stop it so badly,
僕は鍵を探してる
I'm searching for the key.
崩れ落ちそうな 空を支えて
Holding up a sky that seems ready to collapse,
ひとり立ち尽くす
I stand all alone.
ただ、君の 君の側に
I just want to be by your side,
いたいよ
by your side.
アンバランスな
With an unbalanced...
Kissで書かれた ふたりのシナリオ
...kiss, the scenario of the two of us was written.
愛と呼ぶほど 強くなくても
Even if it's not strong enough to be called love,
君のすべてが
everything about you...
痛い
...hurts so much.
ただ、君の 君の側に
I just want to be by your side,
いたいよ
by your side.
アンバランスな
With an unbalanced...
Kissを交わして 愛に近づけよ
...kiss exchanged, let's draw closer to love.
君の涙も 哀しい嘘も
Both your tears and your sad lies,
僕の心に
within my heart,
眠れ
let them rest.
君の心が僕を呼ぶまで
Until your heart calls out to me,
抱きしめあえる 日まで
until the day we can embrace each other.
長い髪なびかせて
Letting my long hair flutter,
悩ましげなボディ
with a tantalizing body,
この都会をハイヒールで
sprinting through this city in high heels—
飛び回れば Big money coming, yeah!
If I leap around, big money coming, yeah!
摩天楼の足下
Beneath the skyscrapers,
時代錯誤の罠
an anachronistic trap.
血迷った 危ない奴らなら
If they're crazed, dangerous folks,
極楽へいかせちゃうわ
I'll send them straight to paradise!
大胆な私の業の中
Among all my bold techniques,
どれでも
whichever one you want...
大胆な私の業の中でどれでも
Out of all my bold techniques,
スキなのをあげる
I'll give you whichever you like.
Bye Bye Sadness. And Find out
行き場のない
because you're a ghost
あなた Ghost だから…
with nowhere to go...
Bye Bye Sadness. And Find out
私が今
right now,
見つけ出して…
I'll track you down...
Ghost Sweeper
吸印もいいけれど
Vacuum seals are fine, but
神通槐はどう？
how about a divine enju wand?
わがままは 許さないわ
I won't forgive any selfishness,
逃がせないの Big money coming, yeah!
I can't let you escape, big money coming, yeah!
コンシャスなドレスから
From form-fitting dresses
ゴージャスなライフも
to a gorgeous life,
いつだって 後からついてくる
they always follow right behind me,
それが私のスタイル
that's just my style.
クールだと 誰かが言うけれど
Someone might say it's cool, but
必ず
without fail,
幸せをあげる
I'll bring you happiness.
Bye Bye Sadness. And Find out
行き場のない
because you're a ghost
あなた Ghost だから…
with nowhere to go...
Bye Bye Sadness. And Find out
私が今
right now,
見つけ出して…
I'll track you down...
Ghost Sweeper
Bye Bye Sadness. And Find out
行き場のない
because you're a ghost
あなた Ghost だから…
with nowhere to go...
Bye Bye Sadness. And Find out
私が今
right now,
見つけ出して…
I'll track you down...
Ghost Sweeper
魂の色は何色ですか
What color is your soul?
「もういっそ 折れたままで」
"I might as well stay broken,"
捨てるほど 逃げ出すほど 強くないよ ほら
I'm not strong enough to just throw it away or flee. Look,
もう一度 鼓動、高鳴る
once again, my heartbeat races.
何が正しいかなんて わからないけど
I don't know what's right, but...
形のないものばかりが
all these formless things
大切になって行く
are becoming so precious to me.
飾らない言葉だけが
Only unadorned words
強く結ばれてる
are tied together so tightly.
また躓いて 転がって それでも砕けない
Stumbling and falling again, yet still never breaking.
魂の色は何色ですか
What color is your soul?
ただ傷ついて 強がって それでも見つけたいよ
Just hurting and acting tough, yet I still want to find it.
魂のカタチ 確かめてるよ
I'm confirming the shape of my soul.
深い地の底で一人 扉と鍵を探す
Alone at the depths of the earth, searching for a door and key.
お伽話は ほら 泡の様に全部消えて
Look, the fairy tales all vanish like bubbles,
葛藤、残像だけ 次の頁へ
leaving only conflict and afterimages to the next page.
伸びてく枝葉が分かれて
The growing branches and leaves divide,
それぞれの道を行く
and each takes its own path.
寂しい思い出だけが
Only lonely memories
強く根を張ってる
have taken deep root.
まだ貫いて 失って それでも挫けない
Still pressing forward, losing things, yet never giving in,
心はどこに 器はどこに
where is the heart? Where is the vessel?
ただ残されて 焼け落ちて それでも伝えたいよ
Just left behind, burning down, yet I still want to convey
魂の日々を 魂の意思を
the days of the soul, the will of the soul.
ずっと
Forever
魂の色は
What color
何色ですか
is the color of the soul?
赤色ですか
Is it red?
青色ですか
Is it blue?
魂の色は
What color
何色ですか
is the color of the soul?
透明な過去に 不透明な明日に
In a transparent past, in an opaque tomorrow,
生きるあなたは何色ですか
what color are you who live within them?
また躓いて 転がって それでも砕けない
Stumbling again, tumbling over, yet never breaking,
魂の色は何色ですか
what color is the color of the soul?
ただ傷ついて 強がって それでも見つけたいよ
Just getting hurt, putting on a brave face, yet I still want to find
魂のカタチ 確かめてるよ
the shape of the soul, confirming it.
ずっと
Forever
イェーイ！
Yeah!
3曲連続でお届けしましたが、
I just performed three songs in a row,
みんな楽しんでますかー？
is everyone having fun?
快適に見れてますかー？
Is the stream running smoothly for you all?
幽遊白書の『アンバランスなKissをして』は月夜ね、映してもらったり、
For Yu Yu Hakusho's \"Unbalance na Kiss wo Shite\", we had the moonlit night projected,
戦闘シーンをイメージして炎に囲まれていたり、
and flames surrounding me inspired by combat scenes,
ダンスの振りにもね、キャラクターの技が入っていたりしておりまして、
and the dance choreography even incorporated the characters' moves!
ゴーストスイーパー美神の『GHOST SWEEPER』にもお札をね、持っている振りがあったり、
And for \"GHOST SWEEPER\" from Ghost Sweeper Mikami, there was choreography holding talisman charms,
あとは幽霊が飛んでいるそんな演出があったりしました。
and an effect with ghosts flying around too.
気づいたかなー？
Did you guys notice?
そして、ソードアート・オンラインの『ANIMA』はいつか歌いたいと思っていた曲で、
And \"ANIMA\" from Sword Art Online was a song I've always wanted to sing someday,
満を持してのお披露目だったんですが、いかがだったでしょうかー？
so this was a long-awaited performance! How did you like it?
いや、かっこよかったなー！すごいなーわため、バキバキだなー！
Man, that was so cool! Watame is amazing, so sharp!
でも！まだこれで終わりではありません！
However! This isn't the end yet!
ここからは鏡、ゲートを使ったギミックや、
From here on, with mirror and gate stage gimmicks,
やってみたかった演出なども入ってくるので、
and effects I've really wanted to try,
さらに盛り上がる爆上げセトリをいっぱいやっていきたいと思います！
I want to perform a ton of hype setlist songs that get everyone even more pumped!
それでは、行ってきまーす！
With that said, here I go!
無敵の笑顔で荒らすメディア
Taking the media by storm with an invincible smile
知りたいその秘密ミステリアス
I want to know her secret, so mysterious
抜けてるとこさえ彼女のエリア
Even her clumsy side is within her domain
完璧で嘘つきな君は
Flawless and deceitful, you are
天才的なアイドル様
the ultimate, genius idol
今日何食べた？ 好きな本は？
What did you eat today? What's your favorite book?
遊びに行くならどこに行くの？
If you go out for fun, where do you go?
何も食べてない それは内緒
Haven't eaten anything; that's a secret
何を聞かれてものらりくらり
Evading everything, no matter what's asked
そう淡々と だけど燦々と
So nonchalantly, yet shining so brilliantly
見えそうで見えない秘密は蜜の味
Secrets seemingly visible yet hidden taste like nectar
あれもない ない ない これもない ない ない
Not that, no, no, no; not this either, no, no, no
好きなタイプは？ 相手は？ さあ答えて
What's your type? Who's your partner? Come on, answer
「誰かを好きになることなんて私分からなくてさ」
\"I just don't understand what it means to love someone\"
嘘か本当か知り得ない
Impossible to know whether it's a lie or the truth
そんな言葉に
With those very words,
また一人堕ちる
another person falls under your spell,
また好きにさせる
falling in love with you all over again.
誰もが目を奪われていく
Everyone is captivated by you,
君は完璧で究極のアイドル
you are the perfect, ultimate idol.
金輪際現れない
Never to appear again,
一番星の生まれ変わり
the reincarnation of the first star.
その笑顔で 愛してるで
With that smile and that "I love you,"
誰も彼も虜にしていく
you captivate each and every one of them.
その瞳が その言葉が
Those eyes, those words—
嘘でもそれは完全なアイ
even if they're a lie, it's total love.
はいはいあの子は特別です
Yes, yes, that girl is special,
我々は端からおまけです
and we're just bonuses from the start.
お星様の引き立て役Bです
We're just sidekick B to make the star shine.
全てがあの子のお陰な訳ない
There's no way everything is thanks to her.
しゃらくさい
How cheeky!
妬み嫉妬なんてない訳がない
Of course there's jealousy and envy!
これはネタじゃないからこそ許せない
This isn't a joke, which is why it's unforgivable!
完璧じゃない君じゃ許せない
An imperfect you is unacceptable,
自分を許せない
I can't forgive myself!
誰よりも強い君以外は認めない
I won't accept anyone other than you, the strongest!
誰もが信じ崇めてる
Everyone believes in and worships you,
まさに最強で無敵のアイドル
truly the strongest, invincible idol.
弱点なんて見当たらない
Not a single weakness to be found,
一番星を宿している
housing the brightest star within.
弱いとこなんて見せちゃダメダメ
You must never show any weakness—no, no!
知りたくないとこは見せずに
Never show what people don't want to see.
唯一無二じゃなくちゃイヤイヤ
You must be one and only—no compromise!
それこそ本物のアイ
That is what true love is all about.
得意の笑顔で沸かすメディア
Rousing the media with your signature smile,
隠しきるこの秘密だけは
keeping this secret completely hidden.
愛してるって嘘で積むキャリア
A career built upon the lie of "I love you,"
これこそ私なりの愛だ
this is my own way of showing love.
流れる汗も綺麗なアクア
Even flowing sweat is beautiful aqua,
ルビーを隠したこの瞼
eyelids concealing glowing rubies.
歌い踊り舞う私はマリア
Singing and dancing, I am Maria,
そう嘘はとびきりの愛だ
yes, lies are the ultimate form of love.
誰かに愛されたことも
Having never been loved by anyone,
誰かのこと愛したことも
nor having ever loved anyone myself—
ないそんな私の嘘が
I hold faith that these lies of mine
いつか本当になること
will someday become the truth.
信じてる
I truly believe it.
いつかきっと全部手に入れる
Someday I'll definitely have it all,
私はそう欲張りなアイドル
for I am such a greedy idol.
等身大でみんなのこと
Just as I am, I want to truly love
ちゃんと愛したいから
every single one of you,
今日も嘘をつくの
so I'll tell lies again today,
この言葉がいつか本当になる日を願って
wishing for the day these words will come true.
それでもまだ
Even so, until now,
君と君にだけは言えずにいたけど
I could never say it to you and you alone, but...
あぁ やっと言えた
Ah, I finally said it!
これは絶対嘘じゃない
This is definitely not a lie...
愛してる
I love you!
あいうえ お菓子した
A-I-U-E-O Sweet treats,
かきくけ こんなにも
Ka-Ki-Ku-Ke-Ko so many of them!
さしすせ ソフトクリーム
Sa-Shi-Su-Se-So soft-serve ice cream,
五臓六腑でいこう
let's satisfy our whole bodies!
たちつて トルテ来た
Ta-Chi-Tsu-Te-To here comes the torte,
なにぬね のり塩
Na-Ni-Nu-Ne-No salted seaweed chips!
はひふへ ホットパイと
Ha-Hi-Fu-He-Ho hot pie,
みんなでぬくぬく
all of us staying nice and warm!
ショートケーキふわり
Fluffy shortcake,
キャンディーぺろぺろ
licking sweet candies.
チョコレートの川で
By the river of chocolate,
綿菓子雲見た
I saw clouds made of cotton candy.
アイスクリームと
Ice cream and
プリンのお城で
in a castle of pudding,
カスタード渡狸
custard Watanuki,
二人のランデブー
a rendezvous for the two of us.
パフェ色サンデー
Parfait-colored sundae,
あんこもハッピー
sweet red bean paste makes me happy!
たい焼きにクリーム
Cream inside taiyaki,
小悪魔ドロップ
mischievous little drops.
カップケーキから
From cupcakes
苺あんみつまで
all the way to strawberry anmitsu,
国境なき sweets
sweets without borders
仲良くなれるよ
can bring us all together!
ぼんやり 夢見てごらん
Dream idly for a moment,
キャラメルみたいにくっつこう
let's stick together just like caramel.
まみむめ モンブラン
Ma-Mi-Mu-Me-Mo Mont Blanc,
やいゆえ ヨーグルト
Ya-I-Yu-E-Yo yogurt!
らりるれ ロールケーキ
Ra-Ri-Ru-Re-Ro swiss roll cake,
渡狸とキスを
sharing a kiss with Watanuki!
あいうえ お菓子した
A-I-U-E-O Sweet treats,
かきくけ こんなにも
Ka-Ki-Ku-Ke-Ko so many of them!
さしすせ ソフトクリーム
Sa-Shi-Su-Se-So soft-serve ice cream,
五臓六腑でいこう
let's satisfy our whole bodies!
のんびり早弁
Eating lunch early at our own pace,
焼きのりあぶって
toasting the roasted seaweed.
おにぎりコロコロ
Rice balls rolling along,
友達ほかほか
feeling warm with friends.
紅葉まんじゅうと
Maple leaf manju and
あんぱんお月さま
anpan moon in the sky.
渡狸に始まり 渡狸に終わる日々
Days starting with Watanuki and ending with Watanuki.
ほんのり 見つめてごらん
Gently look upon
甘くて苦い夕焼けを
the bittersweet evening sunset.
たちつて トルテ来た
Ta-Chi-Tsu-Te-To here comes the torte,
なにぬね のり塩
Na-Ni-Nu-Ne-No salted seaweed chips!
はひふへ ホットパイと
Ha-Hi-Fu-He-Ho hot pie,
みんなでぬくぬく
all of us staying nice and warm!
まみむめ モンブラン
Ma-Mi-Mu-Me-Mo Mont Blanc,
やいゆえ ヨーグルト
Ya-I-Yu-E-Yo yogurt!
らりるれ ロールケーキ
Ra-Ri-Ru-Re-Ro swiss roll cake!
らりるれ ロールケーキ 渡狸とキスを
...roll cake, and a kiss for Watanuki!
ミルフィーユ ワッフル ボンボン
Mille-feuille, waffle, bonbon,
ムース 渡狸パイ
mousse, Watanuki pie!
シュークリーム バナナゼリー
Cream puff, banana jelly,
ババロア 渡狸
bavarois, Watanuki!
ホットケーキ バウムクーヘン
Pancakes, baumkuchen,
渡狸 渡狸
Watanuki, Watanuki!
バター 渡狸 クレープ
Butter, Watanuki, crepe,
ワタヌキ 渡狸
Watanuki, Watanuki!
ワタヌキとごはん
Watanuki and meals!
ワタヌキとおやつ
Watanuki and snacks!
ワタヌキと肉まん
Watanuki and meat buns!
ワタヌキと北京ダック
Watanuki and Peking duck!
みつまめ 渡狸
Mitsumame, Watanuki!
渡狸シロップ
Watanuki syrup!
金時 渡狸
Kintoki, Watanuki!
大盛り渡狸丼
Extra-large Watanuki bowl!
こんがり 思い出色
Golden-brown, colored with memories,
ハチミツみたいにとろける
melting away just like honey.
あいうえ お菓子 した
A-I-U-E, sweet treats for my tongue,
かきくけ こんなにも
Ka-Ki-Ku-Ke, so very many!
さしすせ ソフトクリーム
Sa-Shi-Su-Se, soft-serve ice cream,
五臓六腑でいこう
filling every inch of my belly!
たちつて トルテ 切った
Ta-Chi-Tsu-Te, sliced up a torte,
なにぬね のり塩
Na-Ni-Nu-Ne, salted seaweed flavor!
はっ！ ひふへ ホットパイと
Ha! Hi-Fu-He, with a hot pot pie,
ふたりで ぬくぬく
staying nice and warm, just the two of us!
まみむめ モンブラン やい！ ゆえ ヨーグルト
Ma-Mi-Mu-Me Mont Blanc, yay! Yu-E yogurt!
らりるれ ロールケーキ 渡狸とキスを
Ra-Ri-Ru-Re roll cake, and a kiss for Watanuki!
ワタヌキの甘みと ワタヌキの苦み
Watanuki's sweetness and Watanuki's bitterness,
ワタヌキの酸味で
with Watanuki's tartness,
好き好きラブ・コンボ
it's a lovely, love-filled combo!
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Today's another day of wild, tumbling fun!
うー！ がぉー！
Ooh! Rawr!
高らかに笑い笑えば フレンズ
When we laugh out loud together, we're Friends!
喧嘩して すっちゃかめっちゃかしても仲良し
Even if we fight and cause total chaos, we're still great pals!
けものは居ても のけものは居ない
There may be beasts, but no one gets left out!
本当の愛はここにある
True love is found right here!
ほら 君も手をつないで大冒険
Come on, take my hand and let's go on an adventure!
(ワン・ツー・スリー)
One, two, three!
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Today's another day of wild, tumbling fun!
姿かたちも十人十色
We come in all different shapes and forms,
だから魅かれ合うの
and that's why we're drawn to each other!
夕暮れ空に 指をそっと重ねたら
As we gently overlap our fingers against the sunset sky,
はじめまして
"Nice to meet you,"
君をもっと知りたいな
"I want to get to know you more!"
うー！ がぉー！
Ooh! Rawr!
振り向けば あちらこちらでトラブル
Whenever we turn around, there's trouble left and right!
なんてこった てんでんばらばら ちんぷんかんぷん まとまんない
Good grief! We're all scattered, clueless, and all over the place!
けものですもの 大目に見ててね
But hey, we're animals, so cut us some slack!
みんな自由に生きている
Everyone is living freely,
そう 君も飾らなくたって大丈夫
so you don't have to put on an act either!
はい、どうぞ！
Alright, take it away!
Nice to meet you ジャパリパーク！
Nice to meet you, Japari Park!
今日からはどうぞよろしくね
Let's be great friends starting today!
いつもいつでも優しい笑顔
Always with a gentle smile,
君を待っていたの
we've been waiting for you!
開かれた扉 夢をいっぱい語ったら
Through the open doors, we share all our dreams,
どこまででも
going on and on,
続いてくグレートジャーニー
our great journey continues!
うー！
Ooh!
東へ吠えろ
Roar to the east!
西へ吠えろ
Roar to the west!
世界中に響け サファリメロディ
Ring out across the world, safari melody!
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Today's another day of wild, tumbling fun!
姿かたちも十人十色
We come in all different shapes and forms,
だから魅かれ合うの
and that's why we're drawn to each other!
夕暮れ空に 指をそっと重ねたら
As we gently overlap our fingers against the sunset sky,
はじめまして
"Nice to meet you,"
君をもっと知りたいな
"I want to get to know you more!"
うー！ がぉー！
Ooh! Rawr!
ララララ ララララ
La la la la, la la la la,
Oh, Welcome to the ジャパリパーク！
oh, welcome to the Japari Park!
ララララ ララララララ 集まれ友達
La la la la, la la la la la la, gather around, friends!
ララララ ララララ
La la la la, la la la la,
Oh, Welcome to the ジャパリパーク！
oh, welcome to the Japari Park!
ララララ
La la la la
ラララララララ
La la la la la la la
素敵な旅立ち
A wonderful departure
ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to Japari Park!
Fire! Fire!
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh
Fire! Fire! Fire!
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh
Night of fire
Fire!
Welcome to the broken low, welcome to the famous disco night
Come on, lady, come and go, come on, lady, get me once and right
Not a danger, not a blacky stranger
Rock it, rock it, knock to my door
I'll open, speak my name now, speak it if you know how
Fly to me, get ready for the
Night of fire, you've better, better stay
You've better, better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire, come over, over me
Come over, over the top, you've never been here
Night of fire, you've better, better stay
You've better, better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire, come over, over me
Come over, over the top, you'll have a night of fire
You'll have a night of fire
Welcome to my rocky show, welcome to the fire of the night
Come on, baby, let it go, come on, baby, let me stick you tight
Not a danger, not a blacky stranger
Rock it, rock it, knock to my door
I'll open, speak my name now, speak it if you know how
Fly to me, get ready for the
Night of fire, you've better, better stay
You've better, better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire, come over, over me
Come over, over the top, you've never been here
Night of fire, you've better, better stay
You've better, better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire, come over, over me
Come over, over the top, you'll have a night of fire
You'll have a night of fire
You've better, better stay
The prayer to play
Come over, over me
You've never been here
Night of fire
You've better, better begin
Come over, over the top, you'll have a night of fire
Rock it, rock it
Welcome to my broken low, welcome to the famous disco night
Come on lady, come and go
Come on lady, get me once and right
Not a danger, not a blacky stranger
Rock it, rock it, knock to my door, I'll open
Speak my name now, speak if it you know how
Speak my name now, speak if you know how
Fly to me, get ready for the
Night of fire, you've better better stay
You've better better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire, come over over me
Come over over the top, you've never been here
Night of fire, you've better better stay
You've better better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire, come over over me
Come over over the top, you'll have a night of fire
ということで！
And with that!
ここまでたくさんの、本当たくさんのゲストさんたちと
We've sung and danced up until now with so many...
歌って踊ってきましたが、いかがだったでしょうかー？
...really, so many wonderful guests, but how did you like it?
楽しんでますかー？
Are you having fun?
なかなかね、こんなにホロメンが集まることってないので、
It's not often that this many Holo members gather like this,
もう本当、生誕祭、お祭りって感じで嬉しいです！
so it really feels like a true birthday festival, and I'm so happy!
ゲストさんたちにも大きな拍手をー！
Let's give a big round of applause to our guests as well!
いや、ありがとうみんなー！
Thank you, everyone!
ゲストのみんな、ありがとうー！
Thank you so much to all our guests!
このね、鏡のモニターから登場するという演出をやってみたいなと思って、
I wanted to try out the stage direction of having guests appear from these mirror monitors,
『アイドル』と『スイートパレード』で実現していただきましたー！
and we were able to make that happen during "Idol" and "Sweet Parade"!
わためいと、すこん部さん、エルフレさん、3人さんたちがペンライトを振ってくれてたのも可愛かったし、
It was also so cute seeing the three of them—Watamates, Sukonbu, and Elfriends—waving their penlights,
やっぱりホロメンって可愛いよなー！
Holo members really are just so cute!
あと、『ようこそジャパリパークへ』ではサバンナで肉食動物たちに囲まれて、
Also, for "Welcome to Japari Park", I was surrounded by carnivores on the savanna,
虎のような人間がいたような気もしますが、
and while I felt like there was a tiger-like human there too,
みんながね、仲良くなっていく様子を表現させていただきましたー！
we portrayed how everyone gradually became good friends!
ま、ちょっとね、最後みんなの表情怪しかったけどね。
Though everyone's expressions at the end were a bit suspicious!
そして、『Night of Fire』！
And then, "Night of Fire"!
これはもう、英語の上手なEN・IDメンバーのみんなと一緒に歌いたいと思って、
I wanted to sing this together with the EN and ID members who are so good at English,
横に立って歌っても浮かないように、英語頑張ったんだけど、
so I worked hard on my English so I wouldn't seem out of place standing next to them,
大丈夫だったかな？
but did I do okay?
海外ニキー？
Overseas bros?
「英語上手？ 英語上手？」
"Is your English good? Your English is great!"
ってコメントが来てると思う！
I bet that's what the comments are saying!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
でも！ みんなもっと気になるところがあったかなと思うんですが、
But! I think there was something else everyone was curious about...
車ね！
The car!
攻めてたね！
Pretty bold, right?
あとはパラパラを踊るギリ割るロボね！
And the Giriwaru robot dancing Parapara!
やりたい放題させていただいて、とっても楽しかったです！
Getting to do whatever I wanted was so much fun!
でも！ まだ終わりじゃない！
But! We're not done yet!
ちょっと着替えてくるので、待っててくださいー！
I'm going to go change, so please wait a moment!
よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ。着替えて着替えて、よいしょ、よいしょ。
Yoisho, yoisho, yoisho, yoisho. Changing, changing, yoisho, yoisho.
ふー！
Phew!
はー！ もう着替え終わった。
Haah! Okay, I'm done changing.
さて！ 次の曲なんですが、
Now then! Moving on to the next song...
なんと！ なんかみんな、もう知ってそうだけど、
...amazingly! Though I feel like you all already know...
次の曲は新曲、『灰色の証明』をやりますー！
...for the next song, I'll be performing my new song, "Proof of Gray"!
わためチャンネルにてMV公開中なので、MVもぜひ見てくださーい！
The music video is out on the Watame Channel, so please go check it out!
そして楽曲リリースもしているので、いいなと思ったらぜひ買ってくださいー！
The single is also released, so if you like it, please be sure to buy it!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you for your support!
では、新曲『灰色の証明』、魂を込めて歌います。
Now then, my new song, "Proof of Gray". I'll pour my soul into singing it.
聴いてください。
Please listen.
静寂に包まれた 零地点の感情を
Emotions at ground zero, enveloped in silence,
期待を背負っているのは 私ではないから
for I am not the one shouldering everyone's expectations.
主人公はいつだって 輝いている誰かで
The protagonist is always someone else who shines bright,
見上げるだけじゃ 何にも変わらない
and merely looking up at them changes nothing.
今この時だけの 瞬間的な優位性で
With a fleeting advantage that exists only in this moment,
駆け抜けて
I will race straight through!
灰色の空裂いて “私”の全てを
Tearing through the gray sky, I'll take all of "me"
”運命の物語”に 叩きつけて 打ち砕け
and slam it against this "story of destiny" to shatter it to pieces!
自信は微塵もない あるのは渇望だけ
I don't have an ounce of confidence; all I have is yearning.
ただ自分の生命を 証明しよう
I will simply prove my very existence,
“此処”にいた事を 刻むように
as if carving into stone that I was right "here"!
綺麗な勝ち方は望むべくもない
I can't expect a clean and pretty victory,
華やかさも必要ない
and there's no need for showiness either.
それが私だから
Because that's just who I am.
歴史はいつだって勝者が作るモノ
History is always written by the victors,
だけど記憶はその限りじゃない
but memories aren't limited by that.
今 この時だけは
For just this moment right now,
決断的な刹那性に飛び込んで行け
dive headfirst into this decisive, fleeting instant!
灰色な空描く ”私”の思いが
In the grey sky, my feelings paint a scene
美しき痛みをも乗り越えて書き換えてく
that overcomes even this beautiful pain and rewrites everything!
後悔は1ミリもない あるのは灼熱だけ
There's not a single millimeter of regret; all that remains is burning heat!
ただ自分の生命を蹴り上げるように
As if kicking my very life up into gear!
始まりは些細 もう早どうだっていい
The beginning was trivial, but that doesn't matter anymore.
突き動かされ 指先を伸ばす
Driven forward, I stretch out my fingertips!
現実は残酷だと気付いていないわけじゃない
It's not that I haven't realized how cruel reality is.
諦めるその時は”今”ではなかったらしい
It seems that the time to give up was not "now."
灰色の空紅く もう一度点火して
Igniting the grey sky once more in crimson,
ただ自分の生命を証明しよう
I will simply prove my life!
そこに居た事を刻むように
As if carving the proof that I was here!
Ah...
はい！ということで、新曲『灰色の証明』！
Yes! And so, that was my new song, "Proof of Grey"!
やっと披露できたー！やっと証明できたー！
I finally got to perform it! I finally got to prove it!
聴いてくれて、ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for listening!
この楽曲は、岸田教団&THE明星ロケッツの皆さんに制作していただきまして、
This track was produced for me by Kishida Kyoudan & THE Akeboshi Rockets!
スポーツだったり、みんなが頑張りたい時に力になれるような応援ソングを作りたいと思い、
Wanting to make an anthem that gives strength to everyone during sports or when giving their best,
色々語ったら、かなり熱くてかっこいい楽曲に仕上がりました！
I shared my thoughts with them, and it turned into such a passionate and cool song!
上手くいかないことがあっても、また立ち上がって前に進む、
Even when things don't go well, you pick yourself back up and move forward.
わためにとっても背中を押してくれるそんな特別な楽曲に、今回のライブでなりました！
Through this live performance, it has become a truly special song that pushes me forward as well!
みんなにとってもそうだったら嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy if it feels that way for all of you, too!
こちらの新曲MVいっぱい見て、楽曲もぜひ購入して、わための音楽を応援していただけたらとっても嬉しいです！
I'd really appreciate it if you watch the new MV a lot, purchase the song, and support my music!
目指せ、サードライブ！
Onward to my 3rd solo live!
と、あ、ここでまだ告知していないものが1つありまして。ライブじゃないんですけど...
And, oh, there's one more announcement I haven't shared yet! It's not a live concert, but...
なんと！
guess what!
ドハーン！
Ta-da!
『角巻わためのHave a nice day』書籍刊行決定！
"Tsunomaki Watame's Have a nice day" will be published as a book!
ということで、ハバナイが本になります！
That's right, "HabaNice" is becoming a book!
出版社は『かいけつゾロリ』や『おしりたんてい』などで有名なポプラ社様より、オリジナルグッズ付きで12月に刊行予定です！
Published by Poplar Publishing, famous for "Kaiketsu Zorori" and "Butt Detective", it's scheduled for release in December with original merch!
まだ少し先にはなりますが、楽しみに待っててもらえると嬉しいです！
It's still a little while away, but I'd be so glad if you look forward to it!
そして！ドドーン！
And next! Ba-bam!
今年も角巻わため誕生日記念グッズが受注受付中です！
Orders are now open for this year's Tsunomaki Watame Birthday Celebration merch!
ラインナップを改めて紹介させてくださーい！
Allow me to introduce the lineup once again!
ドドドドドドッ、ドン！
Drumroll... bam!
出たー！ふーみママ描き下ろしの「わためのあったかブランケット」！
Here it is! "Watame's Cozy Blanket" illustrated by Fumi-mama!
なんと、セクシーです！
Look at that, it's sexy!
そして裏面にはわためいとがいまーす！
And on the back, there's a Watamate!
丸めるとね、わためいとの形になりますので2wayでも使えます！
When you roll it up, it takes the shape of a Watamate, so it can be used in 2 ways!
ぜひ温もりを感じてください！
Please be sure to feel the warmth!
そして！ドドドドドドン！
And next! Drumroll... bam!
「わため&わためいと温感マグカップ」！
"Watame & Watamate Thermochromic Mug"!
こちらはモタ先生に描き下ろしていただきまして、
This one was illustrated by Mota-sensei.
最初は夜の風景なんですけど、温かいものを入れていただくと、
At first, it shows a night scene, but when you pour in a hot drink,
その熱を感知して朝の景色に柄が変わるような仕様になっております！
it senses the heat and changes the design into a morning scene!
わための配信を意識してデザインしてもらったので、
The design was made with Watame's streams in mind,
配信を見ながらぜひ温かい飲み物を飲んでくださいね！
so please enjoy a hot drink while watching the streams!
そして、まだあります！
And there's still more!
ドドドドドドドドドドドドドドドド、ダーン！
Drumroll... ta-da!
「わためいとクッション」！
"Watamate Cushion"!
クッションとして使うもよし、飾るもよし、とっても可愛いクッションなので、ぜひお部屋に...
You can use it as a cushion or display it as decoration; it's super cute, so please give it a place in your room...
置いてみてください！
Please try placing it around your room!
最後に！
And finally!
ダダダダダダダダダダ、ドン！
Drumroll... Bam!
来た！わためなりきりアイマスク！
Here it is! The "Become Watame" Eye Mask!
眠っている顔と、
It features a sleeping face,
わためと言えばこれ！
and the iconic expression that defines Watame—
な、表情にしていただきました！
they made it with these two looks!
果たして、需要はあるのか？
I wonder if there's actually demand for this?
気になる方はぜひなりきりアイマスク手に入れてください！
If you're curious, definitely be sure to get your hands on one!
こちらのグッズをフルセットで購入していただいた方には、
And for those who purchase these goods as a full set...
ドロドロドロドロドロ...ドン！
Drumroll... Ta-da!
わための直筆サイン＆メッセージ入りポストカードと、
A postcard with Watame's handwritten signature and message,
角巻わためのショートボイスセット15種類が特典としてついてきます！
plus a set of 15 Tsunomaki Watame short voice clips will come as a bonus!
今年も無制限で直筆を書かせていただく予定なので、
I'm planning to hand-write them without limit this year too,
ぜひこの機会にゲットしてみてください！
so please take this chance to get yours!
ということで、新曲MV公開中！
With that said, my new music video is out now!
楽曲リリース中！
The single is also released!
誕生日グッズ発売中！
Birthday merchandise is now on sale!
12月、カバー内書籍刊行決定！
And my book publication from COVER in December is confirmed!
よろしくお願いいたします！
Thank you so much for your support!
この後は、10時15分からメン限アンコールライブもありますので、
After this, starting at 10:15, we have the members-only encore live,
よかったらメン限、あ、間違えた、メンバーに入っていただいて、引き続き楽しみましょう！
so please join the mem—ah, join the membership, and let's keep having fun!
今年は、なんと2days！
This year was a 2-day live event!
お誕生日たくさんお祝いしてくれて、ありがとう！
Thank you so much for celebrating my birthday with me!
めちゃくちゃうれしかったです！
I was so incredibly happy!
それでは、メン限アンコールライブで会いましょう！
Well then, see you at the members-only encore live!
またねー！
See you later!
これからも夢に向かって一緒に歩いて行こうね！
Let's keep walking together toward our dreams!
お疲れ様でしたー！
Thank you so much for coming!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
え、楽しかった？
Did you have fun?
楽しかった？
Did you enjoy it?
めっちゃ楽しかったねー！
It was so much fun, wasn't it!
もうなんか、あっという間すぎて、
It went by so fast,
え？もう終わっちゃったの？みたいな、
I was like, "Wait, is it already over?"
気持ちでいっぱいなんですけど、
That's how full my heart feels right now, but...
あのー、今日ね、みんなと過ごした時間は、
The time I spent with all of you today...
わための宝物になりました。
has become Watame's true treasure.
みんなにとっても宝物になってたらいいな。
I hope it became a treasure for everyone, too.
なった？
Did it?
よかったー！
I'm so glad!
あのね、わためは武道館を目指して、
You know, Watame is aiming for the Budokan,
これからもぐんぐん進んでいくから、
and I'll keep pushing forward steadily,
ついてきてくれたら嬉しいです！
so I'd be so happy if you keep walking with me!
約束！約束してね！
Promise! Promise me, okay?
ありがとう！
Thank you!
じゃあねー、
Well then,
みんな、気をつけて帰ってね！
please get home safely, everyone!
またねー！
See you again!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
大好きだよ！
I love you all!